Let's see how we can use SMDXX to get the reverse connection. Basically the lateral movement
to the target connection on the organization. So similar to the TSXX, this is also a similar
one and you need to do the post domain. So I already said you can get every information
from the credential access session. So it will the SMDXX will be basically open a semi-interactive
prompt. So you can see, let me do "my/al" and it was running in the system mandatory
level. So in this ticket, the post, we all know where the logware saved. See Windows
system, 32 community logs and let's see the system. First, something get created. So
now you can see this command, copy paste. Let me try to copy paste this command. While
you are performing any kind of investigation in EDR, so the EDR will show this command, this
command, what was going on inside the machine. So here you can find the executor.com/al
and let me execute a few of the commands here like net users and let's see the refresh
that. So you can find the next command that has been executed. You can see it here. Similar
to that, when you try to execute any commands, like any commands, any Windows-based commands,
sorry, EAR, IP config, it will create a service, it will create a service name basically
and you can see IP config and TAR and let's see how given. So this showed much, much
information. Well, you're performing any kind of investigation using an EDR, you need
to really understand what's going on to the command. So you can see a column, a spec and
QC, a code, whoever I slash or and computer name, C# and some bad files. So while performing
any investigation, if you see this command get executed, so that will be a malicious activity,
okay, we will be calling this as an impact command, okay, impact command. So it's really
a bad and malicious one, okay. Let's do some more things here. Here you can find the information
who is the user executor and let's move on to the security log and we can understand
what the, what was going on, okay. We need the event ID of 46244624. Let's do it
without the event ID. This is the log on type 3, network-based log on. This is the user
performed a network-based log on. So once we connected through impacted section, impact
target, using SMBX accord, DX accord, anything. So you can find someone logged into the machine,
you can, if you investigating 4624 events, okay. So we know what was really happening
here, fixed 24 event ID and if you notice the 4624 event ID from security log, the account
was successfully get logged in. So once the account was logged in, you will be getting
4624 log ons. So if you check the log on type 2 is an interactive and 3 is a network-based
log on. So network-based in the sense like if you are using the impact library, you will
be absolutely using a network protocols to connect to the target machine. So your log on
type should be a 3. So in our scenario, if you see this, the log on type was a 3 and the user
who connected from the IP address 18.49, right. So we know our calling machine has
IP address of 18.49. So someone performed some login from IP, the calling machine IP, so we can
understand who connected and from which IP address, he shall connected. So this is how you
need to investigate the system and security logs for 4 and 6 and further investigation
so what's going on inside the machine and what happened inside the machine, okay. So
you will be easily get a log from security and system section. So it's really, really, really
helpful to understand to do a forums, okay. I hope you have a clear understanding about
this, what we did, what are the activities we have come from, how we investigate, what
was going on inside the machine, right. So now what recommendations you will be taking
so if you observe this log on type. So the recommendations you can easily block the IP
address of IP address and you can reset the credentials for the user and you can once you
block the IP address, the detector will not able to login into the any of the machine.
So if you block this IP address in firewall so the detector will not use this IP to login
in any of the machine inside the organization, okay. And once you reset the credentials
for the user, the detector didn't know what was a newly, what was new password, what's
the new credentials for the user, right. So these are the recommendations you can take
and you can do one more thing, you can delete all the service which was created, okay.
Let me check for any kind of service, let me have a C query. So here you can see there
is a service name that was created with R/O DJE-A-N-P, right. So when we, when this was created,
but so he only created a service, R/O-D-J-E-A-N-P, right. So if you delete this service, so
that will be very, very good that the detector will not have anything inside the machine,
right. So this is how you need to perform the investigation and instant response for this
kind of impact attack activity, okay. Let's hop off from here and we'll connect you guys
in the next video, see you, bye bye.